

Alex Norris

Portfolio: alexjnorris.azurewebsites.net/

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alex-norris-09aa9510a

GitHub: www.github.com/AlexJNorris

Medium: www.medium.com/@alex.norris_95444

SUMMARY

I am a recent graduate and aspiring software engineer. I have been coding for the greater part of 7 years and advanced my skills while earning a BS in Computer Science and while working as a research assistant at the University of Missouri – Kansas City. I am excited to grow my skills further and enter the industry!

SKILLS

Languages: C#, C++, Python, Java

Operating Systems: Windows, Ubuntu, Red Hat, Android

Frameworks: Azure, AWS, .NET Core, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Maven, Gradle,

Selenium, Cucumber

Administrative Tools: Kanban, Trello

Certifications: PCEP

Other: Teamwork, Determination, Perseverance

PROJECTS

CI/CD DevOps Pipeline

February 2022

During the Strategio Enterprise Simulator, our final group project was to develop a CI/CD Pipeline. My group employed Jenkins as the main pipelining tool with a GitHub Webhook as the pipeline's trigger and a Kubernetes cluster made with AWS EKS as the endpoint. Inside the pipeline, we built a Docker container,

hosted our Django application, tested using the Django testing framework, then pushed the image to the EKS cluster.

Commerce Bank Web App (Senior Capstone)

August 2021 - December 2021

For my senior capstone, I was a software engineer and project manager for a web application project sponsored by Commerce Bank. With my group, we used ASP.NET Razor Pages to build up our application, using ASP.NET models to build our database dynamically, Microsoft Identity for user management, and Microsoft Azure to host our application online.

Drone Simulation Library

May 2021 - December 2021

Designed and developed a .NET Standard C# library with the purpose of assisting in running simulations involving drone flight for my undergrad research assistantship.

Autonomous Drone Swarm

April 2021 - December 2021

Developed flight decision algorithms to run on drone companion computers using the DroneKit-Python library. Designed an IoT network using the XBee Python API to broadcast commands by RF modules.

EXPERIENCE

Strategio - Technologist

January 2022 - PRESENT

- Tools and Technologies Learned:
- AWS
- Maven
- Jenkins
- Kubernetes

University of Missouri - Undergrad Research Assistant

March 2021 - December 2021

- Worked on programming simulations in support of drone related research.
- Developed drone swarm for live testing.

EDUCATION

University of Missouri — Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

August 2019 - December 2021, Kansas City, Missouri Graduated Cum Laude with a GPA of 3.62

Metropolitan Community College — Associate in Computer Science
May 2015 - July 2019, Kansas City, Missouri

AWARDS

Hack-A-Roo - Third Place Award - University of Missouri-Kansas City Nov 2021